In this video, we'll go through some of
本视频我们来谈一些
the most common and useful plots you can create with pandas.
用 Pandas 绘制的最常用和最实用的图形
Note that the plot methods on a series or
注意 这些为 series 或 DataFrame 绘制图形的方法
data frame are just simple wrappers around matplotlib functions.
都只是基于 matplotlib 函数进行封装的
This is why you might see them used interchangeably.
因此你可能会看到这些绘制方法可以相互替换
Pandas is nice for quick insights,
要快速获取洞见 使用 Pandas 就很不错
but you'll need to use matplotlib to really dive into
但如果要深入研究细节 要自定义可视化界面
details and customize your visualizations.
你就要用到 matplotlib 了
We'll get into this more later on.
稍后我们会更深入地介绍这点
Let's first use census income data to practice part of histograms,
现在我们先用收入普查数据
bar charts, and pie charts in pandas.
在 Pandas 里进行直方图、柱形图和饼状图的部分绘制练习
A really useful line to include when visualizing in
要在 Jupyter Notebook 中进行可视化操作 有行代码特别实用
Jupyter notebooks is the matplotlib inline statement.
那就是 % matplotlib inline 语句
This let's you view your plots in the notebook.
该语句能让你在 Notebook 内部查看数据图
A quick way to view histograms for
有个快捷的办法
all numerical columns in a data frame is a hist function,
可以查看 DataFrame 中所有值列的直方图 那就是 hist 函数
which we could call directly on the pandas data frame.
我们可以直接对 Pandas DataFrame 调用该函数
That was way too crowded.
这样看起来太拥挤了
Let's make our figures size bigger.
我们来把图形的尺寸调大点
Also, we can use a semi-colon to suppress this unwanted output.
另外 我们可以用分号来隐藏那些不需要的输出内容
The hist function can also be called on a pandas series object,
Pandas 的 series 对象也可以调用 hist 函数
so we can call a histogram for one specific column like this.
所以我们可以像这样调出某一列的直方图
Or instead of using hist,
或者 我们也可以不用 hist 函数
the more general plot function,
而改用更加通用的 plot 函数
and specify the type of plot in a parameter.
然后用参数具体说明图形类型
Next, let's plot a bar chart for the education column.
接下来 我们来为教育 (education) 这一列绘制柱形图
For this, we need counts for each distinct value or bar.
为此我们需要知道每种值的数量 也就是每个柱形的高度
This value_counts function aggregates counts for each unique value in a column.
value_counts 函数会汇总一列中每个唯一值的数量
We can call the plot function on this result to create a bar chart.
得出结果后 我们可以调用 plot 函数 绘制柱形图
Similarly, we also need value_counts to plot pie charts.
类似地 要绘制饼状图 我们也要进行 value_counts
Let's create a pie chart for the work class column.
我们来为工作阶层 (workclass) 列绘制饼状图
Awesome. Let's switch to our cancer data
棒极了 现在来处理癌症数据集
set to practice plotting scatter plots and box plots.
进行散点图和箱线图的绘制练习
This next function is really cool for getting quick insight
下一个函数真的很酷 能让你通过散点图
into the relationships among numerical variables with scatter plots.
迅速了解值变量间的关系
It also displays a histogram for each variable.
该函数还会展示每个变量的直方图
We can create a single scatter plot using the standard plot function with
我们也可以绘制单独的散点图 方法是使用标准的 plot 函数
parameters to specify the columns to be used for the x and y axes.
并用参数具体说明用作 x 和 y 轴的列
And finally, the plot function can also be used to create a box plot.
最后 plot 函数也可以用来绘制箱线图